<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>Hyper-threaded thoughts with speculative execution</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000//</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 19:09:38 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2020 19:09:38 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v4.0.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>2020 Resolutions with a bonus lecture</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Reading time: the length of your attention span&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first blog post. Ah, such power and fear as every word I write is immortalized onto search engines and scattered to the vagrants of the web who stumble upon my humble blog with a nonsensical title.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How fitting to start off the new year, the new decade with a draft, my Econ 100A final grade being released, and the close of a toasty holiday season - enough with the musings however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here are my resolutions for this year:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do things that draw from who I am, what my values are, and who I want to be&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take life less seriously&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Learn more in depth the things I think I already know and learn new things I did not know previously&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One may notice that these are incredibly vague - this is my secret key to success. The vagueness is how I fulfilled my 2019 resolutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This brings me to a broader point. New Year resolutions tend to lean towards concrete goals and the fact that these goals are concrete makes it almost futile that one would forget or lose track of them (this is from personal experience as I once promised to bring my grades up). However, goals are an antiquated and short-sighted way to accomplish things. Set up a system instead - build a habit to do something you want to do for at least 5 minutes a day (I personally recommend &lt;strong&gt;at most&lt;/strong&gt; for maximum habit retention).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Goals vs Systems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Goals are concrete and require willpower and getting out of bed (you can’t justify your way out of it)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Systems/habits are lazy, just set the bar low to begin with (habit: play guitar for 3 minutes each day, reality: play guitar for 30 minutes because you got sucked into learning how to play a sad song)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you break a goal, you’re screwed and you lose motivation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you break a system, just start again tomorrow like nothing happened&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For building systems, know what a shock collar is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for reading and please have a happy new year!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 22:22:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000//resolutions/2020/01/03/resolutions.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000//resolutions/2020/01/03/resolutions.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>Resolutions</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
